Guide to the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Yale University, Photographs of Events, Activities, and Individuals
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Yale University, photographs of events, activities, and individuals
1896-1906
RU 748
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.5
The materials consist of photographs and glass negatives documenting student life and activities at the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies (called the School of Forestry prior to 1972), including classroom activities, field trips, summer camps, and alumni events. Also included are pages from the photograph albums of several students.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 24-H (YRG 24-H), Audio-visual materials and memorabilia documenting the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original glass negatives are restricted.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series: 1. Photographs. II. Oversize. III. Folio.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and glass negatives documenting student life and activities at the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies (called the School of Forestry prior to 1972), including classroom activities, field trips, summer camps, and alumni events. Also included are pages from the photograph albums of several students.
Forestry schools and education; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies; Yale University. School of Forestry
- Photographs, Series I
  - Alumni
    - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1910-1911, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2-30)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
    - 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
    - 1951-1952, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
    - 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21-24)
    - 1974, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 27-30)
    - Unidentified (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Dinner, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Reunions (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - 1925, 1940, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 33-35)
  - Alumni-in-Residence, 1979, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Deans, General (sketch) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Camps
    - Canaan Mountain, Great Mountain Forest, Norfolk, CT, (land donated by E. C. Childs, class of 1932)
      - 1940-1967 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - 1941-1967 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - 1950 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Crosset, Arkansas
      - 1912-1966 (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
    - Milford, PA
      - Circa 1900-1901 (Box 2, Folder 43-44)
      - 1901-1903 (Box 2, Folder 45-46)
      - Class of 1905 and instructors, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - "Grey Towers" (residence of Gifford Pinchot), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - 1908 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Class of 1911 (from the scrapbook of J. W. Stokes?), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - 1909-1912 (Box 3, Folder 51-54)
      - Photos from Henry W. Hicock, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - 1922 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - 1920, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - 1938 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - Photos from Henry I. Baldwin, Undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
      - Photos from scrapbook of W. O. Filley, Undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
      - Photos from scrapbook of G. W. Hutton, Undated (Box 3, Folder 61-62)
      - Sawkill Falls (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - Undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - From Henry S. Graves, Undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Missouri (from S. T. Dana, class of 1907) (Box 4, Folder 66-68)
    - Trinity, Texas [?], Undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Camp scenes of people in the community, pets, baptismal
    - Trinity, Texas, Circa 1911 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Trinity, Texas (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Groveton, Texas (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Mojave Valley, California, Circa 1911 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Union Forest, Union, Connecticut, 1930-1940, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Urania, Louisiana, 1917-1941 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - Photo album of Henry Baldwin, Class of 1922
      - Automobiles and logging (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - H. Hardtner, President of Urania Lumber Co (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - People (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Scenes (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Trees (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - photo album of A. E. Wakerman, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Dean Record receiving key to Urania, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Woods, New York, 1912-1916 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Faculty and students, classes
    - Ecology class, 1915, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Ecology class introducing New Haven public school 4th grade class to principles of ecology, Undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - At Greeley Memorial Laboratory (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Wood Technology Lab, Circa 1960 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - In the greenhouse, 1970, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Classroom scene, Undated (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Sage Hall computer room, Undated (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Yale Forestry Center (Valhalla, NY), 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 87a)
    - Students at work, Undated (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Faculty and students, conferences
    - New England Forestry, Circa 1975-1980 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Pacific Science Conference (10th) (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Faculty and students, seminars
    - Industrial Forestry, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Industrial Forestry "Timber Talks", 1955 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Land Use in the New England Environment, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Toby Moffet, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - "Timber as a capital tool: raising capital from timberland assets", 1982 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Prob. Industrial Forum [?] (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Faculty and students, symposia
    - Endangered species, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - East Lyme, CT, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Faculty and students, groups
    - Picnic at Union, CT, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - S. Record, H. Chapman, H. Graves, R. Bryant, R. Hawley, H. Lutz, R. Clapp, J. Boyce, G. Garrett, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Francois Mergen and Herb Winer as graduate students in Soils Laboratory, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Faculty, Circa 1960s (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Berry, Joseph with students (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Berwick, Stephen, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Foster, Charles (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Henson, Walter, with Gordon Mott, Circa 1968 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Ledig, Tom, Circa 1979 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - O'Hare, Art, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Parker, Pamela, Circa 1979 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Reifsnyder, William (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Smith, Bill (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Smith, David M. (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - White, Zeb (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Young, George -- Business Manager, YF & ES, at East Lyme, CT, Undated (Box 6, Folder 113A)
    - Group at Peabody Museum exhibit opening, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Field trips
    - Los Banos, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Lockhart, Alabama, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Priest River Forest, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Keene Forest, 1920s (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Prospect Field trip, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Silver culture, Cooperstown, New York (Otsego Forest Cooperative), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Isle Royale, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Southern trip, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Western trip, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 123-133)
    - Western trip, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Western trip, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 135-136)
    - Terrestrial Ecology soil, 1979-1983 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Union trip [?], 1981 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Silver culture (New Haven Water Co property), 1982 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Miscellaneous
      - General, Undated (Box 7, Folder 140)
      - California, Undated (Box 7, Folder 141)
      - Forest management, Charcoal burning--Henry Haupt. Chapman Management area, 1920s (Box 7, Folder 142)
        - Forest Chapman Sheehan--atop marker dedicated to his great-grandfather, Henry Haupt Chapman, Pachaug State Park (Western CT), 1966, undated
      - Glacier Park (Box 7, Folder 143)
      - Panorama shots (Box 7, Folder 144)
      - Forests abroad (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Forest products (making of) for assistance of WWI war effort. (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Leisure time
    - Spring picnic, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Volleyball game, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - Photograph albums (student)
    - H.B. Eastman
      - Mostly of logging and railroad ties in Sandpoint, ID; Calhoun, LA; Milford, PA; Montana, and Washington State., 1904 (Box 7, Folder 149)
      - Milford Summer Camp, Old Yale Campus, New Haven Green, YFS individuals, and manufacturing of railroad ties., Undated (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - E.A. Lefkof
      - Photographs of people, logging mills/machinery, trees, New Haven, Yale Bowl, scenery, and snakes. (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - T.S. Woolsey, Jr.
      - "Determinative Mineralogy", Undated (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Graves
      - Last portrait of President Abraham Lincoln--a gift of F.H. Meserve to Henry S. Graves, 1865 (Box 8, Folder 153)
      - Commemoration of Bicentennial of George Washington's birthday., 1932 (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - George W. Hutton
      - Group photo (unidentified), Undated (Box 8, Folder 155)
      - Logging (Box 8, Folder 156)
      - People (Box 8, Folder 157-159)
      - People, trees, train tracks, buildings (unidentified), Undated (Box 8, Folder 160)
      - Scenes (Box 8, Folder 161)
      - Snakes (Box 8, Folder 162)
      - Trees (Box 8, Folder 163)
    - Frank R. Oestler
      - Photographs of wildlife and landscape (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Student life
    - Procession featuring: President Roosevelt, Ct Governor McLean, and Yale President Hadley on Elm Street approaching Yale College [Bicentennial, [1901?] (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - Robin Hood Society, 1904-1911 (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - Processional on Old Campus--students receiving diplomas, 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - Convocation--Giamatti, A.B. with students, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Canaling, Undated (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - Student life--miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 9, Folder 171)
  - United States Forestry Service
    - "Foresters at Work" and "Public Relations", 1950-1965 (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - Forests in general, forest management, regeneration, logged forests, logging, forest fire, and erosion, Undated (Box 9, Folder 173)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Plywood airplane, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - Chinese Forestry technicians, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Council of executives in front of Angell Hall, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - Yale Foresters, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 177)
    - 75th Anniversary--New Haven Lawn Club: speeches by Yale President Kingman Brewster, Francois Mergen '52, and John McGuire '42; performance by Whiffenpoofs; guests., 1975 (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Forestry Exhibit at Peabody Museum, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - landscapes and wildlife; copies of art work; miscellaneous, Undated (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Cornell foresters; USSR trip; World War I Major; group photograph, 1914-1919, 1960, undated (Box 9, Folder 179A)
    - People: R. Frank Gregg, Tom Lovejoy, Ruth Patrick, Douglas, Undated (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Redman, and Henry Vaux (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Tufts College--Akerman and Fobes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 181)
  - Glass Plate Negatives
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access to the original glass negatives is restricted.
    - Marsh Hall: library table from the Philippines--before, [1923?] (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Milford Summer Camp (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Camps: Crossett, Ark.; Milford PA; Trinity, TX; Urania, LA, 1904, 1929, undated (Box 10, Folder 184)
- Oversize, Series II
  - Alumni
    - 1904 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1908-1909 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
    - Reunion, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Circa 1920s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Class of 1879, 50th Reunion, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 1935 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - 1937-1939 (Box 11, Folder 8-10)
    - 1953, 1958, 1963, 1968, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 11-15)
  - Training Camps
    - Camp, Spring-Urania, Louisiana, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Camp, Milford, PA, Hawkill Falls, Undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Logging in Wisconsin--Turn of the Century (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Stump Pulling in Minnesota--Turn of the Century (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Memorial rock for A.K. Chittenden, Class of 1900 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Faculty: R. Bryant, S. Record, R. Hewley, J. Tourney, H, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Graves H. Clapman (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Robin Hood Society, 1908-1910 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Haying on Salt Mt., Man with Oven, 1912 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Frank R. Oestler Memorial Collection, Bear--Cornered and Ugly (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Group Pictures, 1915-1916 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Famous Foresters and Practitioners--Newell, F.H., Pratt, Joseph Hyde, Wilson, James (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Folio, Series III
  - 20th reunion, 1920 (Box DR13F41)
  - 30th reunion, 1930 (Box DR32F99)
  - Milford, PA training camp, 1909 (Box DR13F41)